MICHAEL HENDERSON -

SYSTEM ENGINEER, INFRASTRUCTURE TECH, IT SPECIALIST

360-410-2559



CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS SysOps Admin
 CompTIA A+
- Cisco CCENT
- CompTIA Project+
- CompTIA Security+
 CompTIA Cloud+
- CompTIA Cloud Essentials+

PROFILE

Cloud & Systems Administration graduate, with 5+ years of related work experience and several industry certifications from Cisco, CompTIA, and AWS. Diverse and proven knowledge of server infrastructure, client/desktop support, and information security. Consistently recognized as being a model classmate and employee, and being helpful, respectful, and easy to approach by my peers.

SKILLS

- Network Routing & Switching
- AWS, Azure Cloud Computing
- Windows, Linux, and MacOS
- ESXi and Hyper-V Virtualization
- Windows Server '08 '16R2 '19
- Active Directory + Group Policy
- PowerShell, Bash, Java, C, Python
- HTML, PHP, JS Web Development
- PKI & TLS Certificates
- Helpdesk & User Support

EXPERIENCE

Information Security Intern – Premera Blue Cross

06/2020 - 09/2020

- Enabled business critical software by reviewing and accrediting risk, in accordance with HITRUST and SOC standards.
- Rewrote and improved administrative task automation scripts using PowerShell and reduced overall file-size by eliminating redundancy.
- Categorized and reviewed HITRUST audit findings to enable remediation prioritization.
- Served as a Subject Matter Expert on a Lean process improvement workshop, empowered to improve core business processes.

IT Specialist – Industrial Credit Union

04/2019 - 12/2019

- Performed multi-site, organizational hardware/software upgrade from Windows 7 to Windows 10, including providing end-user training.
- Architected Active Directory redesign to implement Role-Based Access Control in the business.
- Championed proper SSL and security practices, and development/management of internal PKI for business-critical applications.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University

July 2020

Bachelor in Cloud & Systems Administration

Whatcom Community College

June 2019

Associate in Cybersecurity

Computer Lab Aide – Whatcom Community College

08/2018 - 06/2019

- Provided high-level support to end-users and technical support to labs; Lab equipment included 24+ Cisco routers and switches, and 100+ Windows 10 systems.
- Gained increasingly technical roles, such as web development, deploying a new industrial systems lab, and system administration roles within ESXi, Windows Server 2016R2, and HP networking systems (i.e. VLANs, trunking, etc.).
- Oversaw Active Directory (i.e. file shares, user accounts, backups, and hardware), provisioned 18 virtual machines in Hyper-V for lab use, and architected an entire mixed-security VM environment for extracurricular cybersecurity groups.